I'd appreciate it if you'd stop that, esper.
（駒場(こまば)）
少しは
加減してほしいものだな
能力者
Komaba Ritoku.
（結標(むすじめ)）
駒場利徳(りとく)
Who would've thought I'd run into the target first?
（結標）
こちらが先に―
ターゲットと
ぶつかってしまったわ
Destroying all of our dispersed money caches at once seems a little childish, don't you think?
各所に
分散させておいた資金を
一度に
全部 剥ぎ取ろうとは
いささか
大人げないと思うが
All I'm doing is crushing my targets.
こちらは破壊目標を
確実に たたくだけ
I don't give a damn about your funds.
活動資金のことなんか
知ったことではないわ
Move Point, eh?
座標移動(ムーブポイント)か　やっかいな力だ
A troublesome power.
Do you think it's only troublesome?
やっかい程度で収まると思う？
ああ… まあ そうだな
やっかい以上に憎らしい
I suppose...
It's much more despicable than troublesome.
I'll end you in one blow between the eyes.
（結標）
眉間にぶち込んで
終わらせてあげるわ
（結標）ハッ…
（駒場）遅いぞ
Too slow!
I'm taking this very seriously.
こちらだって真面目にやる
I deserve some kind of handicap for facing such a monster, don't I?
貴様のようなバケモノと
戦うんだ
これくらいのハンデが
あってもいいだろう
You won't hit me!
当たらんよ！
（蹴る音）
That mobility...
（結標）
この運動性能…
You have Hard Taping under your clothing, don't you?
服の内側に発条包帯(ハードテーピング)を
仕込んでいるのね？
フフッ… 音波伸縮性の
軍用特殊テーピング
Getting my hands on this military-grade ultrasonic wave elastic taping wasn't easy.
手に入れるのに苦労した
You do know that with all its defects, you can't use it without repercussions, right?
そんな欠陥品を
生身の体に使って―
ただで済むと思うの？
I'm prepared for that.
その程度の覚悟は
決まっている
I need to finish this.
早急に決着をつけよう
ンンッ！
I still have a lot of other things to do!
俺の前には―
やるべきことが
山積しているのでな
Too weak!
（駒場）薄いな
（結標）ハッ…
Do you really think you can stop me with a shield like this?!
その程度の膜では
この俺を止めることはできない！
フン…
Too easy.
あっけない
#24 Skill Out
Armed Group
Now then...
Seems like her part's over with, too.
あっちのノルマも
終わったみたいだし
Oh, man.
ヤダねえ　１人で残業ってのも
Looks like I'm the last on—
（駒場）それなら休ませてやろうか
（ｱｸｾﾗﾚｰﾀ）ああ？
I guess I can't keep you waiting, then.
Huh?
（ｱｸｾﾗﾚｰﾀ）ああ？
（駒場）アクセラレータか
Accelerator.
So you're Komaba Ritoku.
駒場利徳だな？
一応 理由を尋ねてやろうか
Let me ask you what the reasoning behind your plan is.
You wouldn't be interested in Skillout's reason for attacking espers.
スキルアウトが
能力者をたたく理由なんて―
聞いても面白いものではない
フッ… 街を混乱させたうえで
無差別攻撃ってとこか
So I take it you're going to attack everyone indiscriminately after you send the city into chaos?
無差別ではない
標的ぐらいは こちらで選ぶ
No, not indiscriminately.
We do a good job of choosing our targets.
You seem pretty calm.
（ｱｸｾﾗﾚｰﾀ）
なかなか余裕があるみてえだが
今の状況 つかめてんのか？
Don't you understand what situation you're in right now?
I killed her.
俺が殺した
（駒場）
話に聞いていたのとは違う
This is different from what I'd been told.
Social defects are supposed to go all out with their powers at this point.
日陰者たちは
普通なら ここでは ためらわない
Is that so?
（ｱｸｾﾗﾚｰﾀ）
そうかい… 知ってるか？
Hey, did you know?
People who confront me tend to end up sliced up.
俺の前に立ったくそ野郎は
普通なら ミンチになるんだぜ
That electrode is a transmitter for some sort of electronic information, right?
その電極 何らかの電子情報を
送受信しているな？
何だ？　これは
What's this?
Chaff Seeds.
“攪乱の羽(チャフシード)”
電波攪乱(かくらん)装置の一種だよ
They're an electromagnetic radar countermeasure.
ウワッ！
Damn it!
野郎！
（銃声）
Time for you to splatter!
（駒場）
真っ赤に はじけろ
Checkmate.
（駒場）
チェックメートだ
This is the last decision you'll make.
最後に選べ
どこを撃ち抜いて殺してほしい？
Where should I shoot to kill you?
Are you going to make the guiltless into the misfortunate?
（ｱｸｾﾗﾚｰﾀ）
そうやって 何の罪もない人間から
順番に 不幸にするつもりか
Don't screw around with me, you shithead!
ふざけんじゃねえぞ！
このくそ野郎が！
Wha—
Why is your reflection working?
（駒場）
なぜ
お前の反射が生き返っている？
Are you stupid?
バッカじゃねえの？　チャフってな
Chaff Seeds cause electromagnetic scrambling by sending bits of metal into the air.
空気中に金属箔(きんぞくはく)をばらまくことで
電波障害を起こすんだよ
The counter is simple.
なら 簡単だ
漂ってる金属箔をどけちまえばいい
Just get rid of the metal by, for example, ventilation.
例えば 換気するとかな
Now then...
（ｱｸｾﾗﾚｰﾀ）さ～てと
（駒場）ンッ…
（ｱｸｾﾗﾚｰﾀ）
ンッ… レベル０のぶんざいで
レベル５にケンカを売る その根性
You picked a fight with a Level 5, you Level 0.
もう一度 見せてもらおうか
Do you have the balls to do it again?
（駒場）ンッ…
（ｱｸｾﾗﾚｰﾀ）遅(おせ)えんだよ！
Too slow!
チェックメート …だよな？
Checkmate, right?
Just being a Level 0 doesn't make you evil.
レベル０っていうだけじゃ
悪にはならねえ
People say you guys are a bother because groups like Skillout cause problems!
（ｱｸｾﾗﾚｰﾀ）
ああいう連中が
ジャマ者扱いされてんのは―
ひとえに お前らみてえな
スキルアウトがはしゃいでるせいだ
Obtain rights?
（ｱｸｾﾗﾚｰﾀ）
権利の獲得？　安全の保証？
ばかばかしい
Secure safety?
Don't give me that shit!
Didn't you realize that those actions were slowly closing around your own neck?!
そういった行動が―
お前の首を絞めてるってことぐれえ
気づかなかったのか？
フッ… もしもの話をしようか
Let's talk about a hypothetical situation.
The humanity of those with strong powers does not play a factor.
能力者としての優劣に
人格的な問題は考慮されない
Some are ugly-hearted people, using their powers for whatever purpose they so choose.
中には強大な力を振りかざすだけの
醜い人間もいる
What if those people were playing a game to see who could kill the most Level 0's
そういうヤツらが
組織されたスキルアウト以外の―
レベル０だけを競って襲うゲームが
はやっているとしたら
who didn't belong to some organization?
What would you do?
お前は どうする？
フッ… いずれ こういう結末を
招くのは分かっていたが
I knew this day would eventually come.
You bastard...
この野郎…
Looks like you and I are in similar circumstances right now.
どうやら 今の俺とお前は
同じような境遇にいるらしいな
Here's a present.
手土産だ
このブザマな光景を胸に刻んでおけ
Carve this ugly scene into your heart.
（海原(うなばら)）
ご苦労さまです
Well done.
死体の搬送 および 証拠の隠滅は
こちらで行います
We will transport the bodies and eliminate the evidence.
I'll send the garbage truck over, so get a ride from him.
例の収集車を送りますので
そちらに乗ってください
いや　こっちは勝手に帰る
No, I'll go home on my own.
That's fine, but please avoid meeting anyone.
（海原）
かまいませんが
知人と遭遇するのは避けてください
我々は紛れることに…
（電話を切る音）
We need to avoid expos—
生きてんだろう？　結標淡希(あわき)
You're alive, aren't you, Musujime Awaki?
途中から見せてもらっていたけど
どこで気づいたのかしら
I started watching somewhere in the middle, but when did you notice?
フン… バレバレなんだよ
うっとうしいマネしやがって
It was obvious.
Don't give me that crap.
（結標）
フフッ… 命の恩人に対して
そういう言葉遣いでいいのかしら？
Is that how you should be talking to the one who saved your life?
“命の恩人”ね　死ぬまで言ってろ
My savior, eh?
Take those words to your grave.
Oh, you're going somewhere?
あら　どこかに寄っていくの？
It's nothing important.
大したことじゃねえ　残業だよ
Just some overtime.
（アクセラレータ）
サービス残業
Free overtime.
（ｱｸｾﾗﾚｰﾀ）
あ～あ…
残業のせいで 結構 遅れちまったな
Man...
This extra work took a while.
チッ… コンビニ寄って
コーヒーでも買ってくか
I guess I'll stop by a convenience store and get some coffee.
（美鈴(みすず)）ウ～ン…
（ｱｸｾﾗﾚｰﾀ）うん？
（美鈴）
き… 気持ち悪い… アア…
I-I don't feel too good...
（ｱｸｾﾗﾚｰﾀ）
フン…
うん？　あのツラ
どっかで見たような気が…
Wait, that face...
I feel like I've seen her before.
Who the hell is this?
何なんだ？　こいつ
Hi there, I'm Misaka Misuzu-san!
はいは～い　御坂(みさか)美鈴さんですよ
（美鈴）アア～ッ…
（ｱｸｾﾗﾚｰﾀ）ウワッ！
Why you...
て… てめえ
趣味は数論のお勉強　特技は水泳
おっぱいは91センチで～す
My hobby is studying number theory, I'm good at swimming,
and my boobs are 91 centimeters!
あっ いけね
私 結婚してたんだった
Oh right, I'm married.
ほら　パパに悪いから
なれなれしく触んじゃねえって
C'mon, Daddy will be mad so don't touch me!
Wait...
あれ？　断崖大学の―
Do you know where Dangai University's database center is?
データベースセンターって
どこだっけ？
Hey white-hair, do you know anything about it?
ねえ 白いの
あんた 何か知ってる？
Hey, don't ignore me white-hair!
（美鈴）
あっ！　無視すんなよ 白いの！
（つかむ音）
ウワッ！
（美鈴）
だから 美鈴さんは―
Hey...
Misuzu-san has to go study there.
これから そこで
お勉強しなくてはいけないのです
プハァ～ッ…
How the hell should I know?!
知るか ボケ！
そこらのタクシーでも捕まえてろ！
Call a taxi or something!
I kiss everyone as long as they're younger, man or woman!
私は 年下なら 男の子でも
女の子でもチューしちゃうんだぞ
（美鈴）プハァ～ッ…
（ｱｸｾﾗﾚｰﾀ）ンッ…
I have no idea what the hell you've been talking about!
さっきから
意味の分かんねえことばっか―
言ってんじゃねえ！
But don't you think that croquettes qualify as a sort of nabe-type meal then?
（上条(かみじょう)）
それを言ったら コロッケだって
鍋のひとつだと思うわけよ
You put bread crumbs on the stuffing then put it in a pot of hot oil.
目の前でパン粉をつけておいた具を
油の中に入れていくのがだな…
Well, I guess that's also because anything tastes better right when it's made.
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）
作りたてが おいしいっていうのは
そのとおりかも
あっ！　それなら いっそ
私の前で当麻(とうま)が料理を作って
So that means that eating everything you cook right as you're making it would taste the best?!
それを私が全部 食べちゃうのが
いちばん おいしいんじゃ…
（美鈴）ああっ！　あんた 確か…
（上条）うん？
H-Hey! I know you!
M-Misaka-san?!
（上条）
み… 御坂さん？
Misuzu-san is going to go to sleep now...
美鈴さんは
もう何も要りません
ウ～ン…
Oh, wait. I haven't done my stretches or taken off my makeup.
あっ いけね
ストレッチしてないし
乳液も塗ってないじゃん
ちくしょう…
Damn...
努力を怠ると
すぐ肌に返ってくる
I can't believe I have to go through all this effort all the time...
ウウ… 吐きそう
I think I'm going to throw up.
（上条）あ… あの…
（美鈴）フフッ…
U-Um...
（上条）
ウワッ！
Woohoo! I got myself a young guy!
おっしゃー！　年下の坊やゲット！
こんな時間にブラブラしちゃって
美琴(みこと)ちゃんは どうしたのよ？
What's Mikoto-chan gonna do when she finds out you've been wandering around at night?
（美鈴）プハァ～ッ…
（上条）アアッ！
H-Help me, Index!
（上条）
た… 助けて インデックス！
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）クッ…
（美鈴）そういや―
Huh? Who's that girl?
そっちの子って誰だっけ？
フン！　別に あなたみたいな人に
名乗る名前なんてないかも
I have no reason to tell someone like you my name.
Why you little...
（美鈴）あんだと？　この！
（上条）アッ！
ああっ…
インデックス　私はインデックス！
Index! I'm Index!
ねえねえ　断崖大学の
データベースセンターって―
Hey, hey.
Do you know where the Dangai University database center is?
（美鈴）どこだっけ？
（上条）はぁ？
Huh?
They told me the resources I need to write my university report are only in Academy City, so I had to come here.
大学のレポートを書くための資料が
学園都市にしかねえっつう話だから
わざわざ ここへ
やって来るしかなかったのです
I see.
（上条）
はぁ… なるほど
う～ん… そうだ！
電話番号とアドレス 交換しよう
Oh, yeah!
Let's exchange phone numbers and e-mail addresses!
That's sudden!
唐突！
Okay, I'll put your number in my "Friends" category!
君の番号は“友達”のカテゴリーに
登録しとくからね！
Misaka...
御坂… 偶然？
Was it a coincidence?
いや あのガキに関係あることか
No... she isn't involved in this.
Accelerator. Do you need something?
（男性）
アクセラレータ　何か用ですか？
They intercepted the call...
（ｱｸｾﾗﾚｰﾀ）
チッ… 割り込まれたか
So, you bastard, I'm guessing you're the head of GROUP?
悪趣味な野郎だ
お前がグループの上か
I can answer any questions you have.
（男性）
質問の内容を承ります
何もねえよ
こっちのことは こっちでやる
I don't have any.
I have my own problems to deal with.
Your own problems, huh?
（男性）
“こっちのこと”ですか
まいりましたね
That's a shame.
I had something I wanted to talk to you about, but since you're busy...
お耳に入れておきたい案件が
あったのですが
（ｱｸｾﾗﾚｰﾀ）ああ？
（男性）ちょうど良かった
Oh, what perfect timing.
It's starting now.
（男性）今 始まったところですよ
（ｱｸｾﾗﾚｰﾀ）なに？
What?
That Misaka Misuzu-sama applied for permission to use the Dangai University database center, so we have attacked it.
（男性）
かの御坂美鈴さまより―
断崖大学のデータベースセンターの
使用申請が―
出されていましたものですから
そちらを襲撃させていただきました
（ｱｸｾﾗﾚｰﾀ）襲撃？
（男性）ええ
Attacked?
Correct.
Who is this Misaka?
その御坂ってのは何者(なにもん)だ？
Misaka Misuzu-sama is the mother of a Ms. Misaka Mikoto.
（男性）
御坂美鈴さまは
御坂美琴嬢の母親に当たります
Do you know of the Recovery Movement?
“回収運動”という言葉は
ご存じですか？
Something about parents taking their kids elsewhere before the war breaks out.
開戦前に保護者がガキを取り戻して
地方へ移ろうとかっていう…
Having a great number of students leave Academy City is a problem, you know.
（男性）
多くの学生たちが
学園都市を離れてしまうと―
いろいろ困るのですよ
Misaka Misuzu-sama is acting as a representative for the parents of the students in this case.
今回の件では 御坂美鈴さまは
保護者代表のような立場にあります
So we decided to stop her short.
…で
ここで摘んでおくことにしました
Will you help us, Accelerator?
あなたも参加しますか？
アクセラレータ
What was that?
なんだと？
Originally, Skillout was hired to take care of it, but...
（男性）
今回の件は
スキルアウトに依頼したのですが
Well, they're rather bad at it.
いやぁ 手際が悪い
If you help us out then—
アシストしていただけるのであれば
お断りだ　俺の人生は 俺のもんだ
No thanks.
My life is my own.
What you're planning over there has nothing to do with me.
そっちに どんな思惑があるかは
関係ねえ
I see.
（男性）
そうですか
なら 早く帰宅してください
Then please hurry home.
それまで あなたの能力は
こちらで預かっておきますね
I'll take care of your power until then.
なっ！　お前 電極に細工を…
You bastard... You tampered with—
（男性）
では 失礼させていただきます
おやすみなさい アクセラレータ
I'll be taking my leave, then.
Good night, Accelerator.
Misaka Misuzu, was it?
御坂美鈴 …だったか？
こいつを助けりゃ
上は歯ぎしりするんだよな？
I'll bet I'll piss him off quite a bit if I go save her.
That bastard...
（ｱｸｾﾗﾚｰﾀ）
あの野郎…
チッ… 今は そっちじゃねえ
Now's not the time for that.
さ～てと
All right, let's go save her in the most unconventional way possible...
最も救いから遠い方法で
何もかもを血みどろに救ってやるよ
By covering the streets with blood.
（ｽｷﾙｱｳﾄ）
ちくしょう　誰だよ？
セキュリティー切り忘れたのは
Damn it, who forgot to disable the security systems?
We don't have time!
（ｽｷﾙｱｳﾄ）
とにかく時間がねえ
例の女を捜すぞ
Let's find that woman.
What's going on?
（美鈴）
どうなってんのよ？
確かに
警備員(アンチスキル)に電話したはずなのに…
I already called Anti-skill...
Mikoto-chan
Those guys are probably Skillout!
そいつらは多分 スキルアウトだ
（美鈴）
スキルアウト？
"Skillout"?
（上条）
レベル０たちが集まって
武装したギャングみたいなもん
They're like a gang of Level 0's that have banded together.
Why are they after me?
（美鈴）
私を狙うのは なぜ？
I don't know.
そいつは知らないけど…
あっ 御坂さん
あんた 娘には電話したのか？
Misaka-san, have you tried calling your daughter?
（美鈴）えっ？
（上条）あいつは―
She's one of only seven Level 5's in the city.
学園都市に
７人しかいないレベル５だ
If you haven't yet—
（上条）もしも まだ…
（美鈴）待って
Wait! I don't want to call her!
（美鈴）
美琴ちゃんはパス　私の問題に
あの子を巻き込んだら…
If I drag her into my problems like this, I won't be able to face her again.
もうあの子に顔を合わせられないわ
（上条）
分かった
All right.
Then, I'll go.
それなら 俺が行く
What? I didn't call you to—
（美鈴）
えっ？　君に そこまで頼んでは…
（浜面(はまづら)）
女は まだ見つかんねえのか？
Have you still not found that woman?!
I'm asking you a question, damn it!
まだ見つかんねえのかって
聞いてんだよ くそが！
ンッ… くそ　駒場の野郎
自分だけ あっさり死にやがって
Damn Komaba, why'd he have to go off and die like that?
残された俺たちは
どうすりゃいいんだ？
What are those of us left behind supposed to do now?
Hamazura here.
浜面だ　ターゲット発見
こちらで始末する　お前たちは…
We've found the target.
We'll deal with her, so you guys—
（ｽｷﾙｱｳﾄ）ウッ！　てめえ…
（無線:銃声）
警備員(アンチスキル)か？
Anti-skill?
（ｱｸｾﾗﾚｰﾀ）
ハ～イ　くそ野郎ども
Hi there, you little bastards.
I'm going to reward you guys with a one-day round trip to heaven.
お前らに 天国の日帰り旅行を
プレゼントしてやる
あまりにも いい所だから―
Though you might enjoy it so much you won't feel like coming back!
帰る気 起きなくなるかもな！
（無線:銃声）
Five of them, all armed...
（上条）
５人か… 全員 銃を持ってるな
Let's hope this is bulletproof.
防弾 …だよな？
Is she stupid?!
アホか あの女！
くそ… 相手が体勢を取り戻す前に
銃の入ったカバンに飛びつけば…
Damn it...
If I can grab the bag with the gun before they recover...
（ｽｷﾙｱｳﾄ）おい
（青白）冗談だろう？
Whoa dude!
You're kidding—
ンッ… バカ野郎！
Idiots!
（銃声）
ウワッ！
（ｽｷﾙｱｳﾄ）この！
（美鈴）アッ！
You little...
（ｽｷﾙｱｳﾄ）この！
（美鈴）ウウ…
Misaka-san, let's run!
御坂さん 逃げるんだ　御坂さん！
Misaka-san!
（美鈴）えっ？
（上条）早く！
Hurry!
（ｽｷﾙｱｳﾄ）くそ！
（空撃ちの音）
Shit!
Interesting.
面白(おもしれ)え　まだ依頼を諦めねえとは
いい根性じゃねえか
You've got guts sticking to your job even after all this.
（ｽｷﾙｱｳﾄ）こっちだ！
（ｱｸｾﾗﾚｰﾀ）チッ…
裏口か…
とりあえず 人の多い所へ行こう
The back door...
For now, let's head somewhere crowded.
（浜面）何なんだよ…
（上条･美鈴）ハッ…
Why...
Why did you show up with such timing?
（浜面）
なんで
このタイミングで やって来れた？
あの依頼そのものがダミーで
俺たちはハメられたのか？
Don't tell me she's a dummy, and we were just set up by the guy who requested this job?
依頼だと？
Request?
Komaba got himself killed,
（浜面）
駒場の野郎が殺されて
路地裏に対する制圧作戦を
回避するには―
and then we had no choice but to cooperate with them,
or else we'd be wiped out in their back alley take-back operation...
ヤツらに取り入るしかねえと
But you were planning on just dumping us from the very beginning!
くそ…
最初から見捨てる腹だったのか！
I'm only here because she called me.
俺は この人から
電話を受けて やって来ただけだ
フフフッ… つまり あれか
So you're telling me that I, Hamazura Shiage, will die here,
この浜面仕上(しあげ)の人生が
ここで終わるっつうのに
and I can't even say that I got caught in a trap,
巨大な陰謀に巻き込まれたとか
とんでもない策士がいたとか
or was just a pawn in some grand scheme?
そういうふうに
ごまかすこともできねえってのか
ハハハハッ…
たまんねえな おい！
I can't take this!
I need to beat the crap out of someone!
殴り殺さなくちゃ気が済まねえよ！
下がってろ！
Get back!
But wait, if you're not associated with them, then the job is still valid, right?
あ～あ… てことは あれだよな？
てめえが
ヤツらと関係ないってことは―
依頼は まだ有効ってわけだ
I just need to bring her corpse to them...
ターゲットの死体を持っていきゃ…
フフフッ…
Say that again, you bastard!
もう一度 言ってみろ てめえ！
Don't give me that crap.
ふざけんな
人の命を何だと思ってやがる
Is that all you think of a human life?
We have no choice!
しかたねえだろう！
こうでもしないと―
If we don't do this, we Level 0's have no chance of survival!
俺たちレベル０は
生きていけねえんだ！
Don't lump me in with you.
（上条）一緒にするんじゃねえよ
（浜面）なに？
What?
（上条）
全てのレベル０を―
Don't lump all the Level 0's in with trash like you!
てめえみてえな野郎と
一緒にするんじゃねえよ
あっ そうだ
てめえは能力を一度も…
Come to think of it, you haven't used any powers...
There are Level 0's all over Academy City.
（上条）
レベル０の人間なんざ
学園都市にはゴロゴロいる
They go to school like everyone else,
そいつらは
みんな 普通に 学校に通って
make friends like everyone else,
普通に友達作って
普通に生活してんだよ
and live normally like everyone else.
Yet, by doing all this, the one belittling Level 0's the most is you!
てめえ自身が いちばん
レベル０をバカにしてんじゃねえか
You're really the same as us?
てめえも俺たちと同じ…
I'm not the same!
（上条）
同じじゃねえよ
Sure, I'm a Level 0, but I'll never stoop to becoming minus like you guys by trampling over the lives of others!
確かに 俺はレベル０だけどな
他人の足を引っ張って喜ぶほど―
マイナスになったつもりは
ねえんだよ
Minus?
マイナス？
俺たちがマイナスだと？
You're calling us "minus"?
People like us in Skillout are a hundred times better than the people who have power and don't use it to help!
力があっても 何も与えてくれない
あんな連中に比べれば―
俺たちスキルアウトのほうが
100倍マシだろうが！
Tell me then, when was the last time you reached out your hand to help someone?
じゃ　そういうてめえは
助けを求めてる人に
（上条）手を差し伸べたのか？
（浜面）ハッ…
（上条）
もしも 能力者に
反撃するだけの力を使って―
If you used that strength to save those in need rather than fighting espers,
困っている人に
手を差し伸べていれば―
then Academy City in its entirety wouldn't look down on you!
てめえらは学園都市中の人たちから
認めてもらえたはずなんだよ
Shut up!
黙れ！
そういうふうに生きてきた―
Our Level 0 leader, Komaba Ritoku, lived exactly like that and was killed for it!
駒場利徳ってレベル０のリーダーは
殺されたよ
He tried to protect the weak!
場違いにも
弱者を守ろうとしてな！
Even then, he had something you guys don't!
だが そいつには
てめえにないものがあったはずだ
That's why he fought to the very end!
だから 最後まで
逃げずに戦ったんじゃねえのか？
He didn't fight to protect the weak, he fought to protect his friends!
（上条）
弱者なんて呼ばずに
仲間を守るために！
Shut the hell up!
ふざけんな！
レベル０のくせに
ロクな力も持ってないくせに
You're a Level 0 with no power to speak of, and you're looking down on us?!
俺たちをバカにしやがって！
（上条）
てめえらがバカにされてきた理由は
力のあるなしなんかじゃねえ
The reason people look down on you isn't because you have no power.
Stand up for yourself and fight that lame illusion!
そんなつまんねえ幻想なんて
自分で どうにかしやがれ！
You damned bastard!
このくそ野郎が！
（殴る音）
To tell you the truth, I actually came here to take Mikoto-chan back.
（美鈴）
実を言うとね
私は美琴ちゃんを連れ戻しに来たの
But I'm not worried anymore.
でも まあ 安心したよ
With you kids around to protect her, I guess there won't be any problem.
君たちみたいな子が
美琴ちゃんを守ってくれれば―
（美鈴）何の問題もないって話よ
（上条）“君たち”？
"You kids"?
Were you guys ordered to punish me or something?
（ｱｸｾﾗﾚｰﾀ）
上に言われて
俺に罰則でも与えに来たか？
Don't be silly.
（土御門(つちみかど)）
まさか
Misaka Misuzu no longer wishes to take her daughter away from Academy City.
御坂美鈴の件について
娘を学園都市から
連れ出そうという気はうせたらしい
As a result, her kill order has been suspended.
（土御門）
なので 殺害は中止
上が
そんな曖昧な結論で認めんのか？
Are the higher ups really okay with such a vague conclusion?
They'll accept it.
（土御門）
認めるだろうさ
主に海原のバカが
１人で頑張ったからな
Mostly due to the efforts of this idiot Unabara here.
Well... that boy looks like he's fulfilling his promise that he'd protect the world around someone I care for.
（海原）
いやぁ　あの少年には―
こちらの思い人と
その周囲の世界を―
守ってもらうという約束を
果たしていただけたようですし
So I thought I should put my own guts into my work too.
自分も頑張らないといけないなと
思いまして
I may have overworked myself a little though.
少しだけ 肩に
力が入り過ぎてしまったんですよ
さっきから ずっと この調子で
具体的な回答を控えているのよ
This guy's been avoiding giving us concrete answers the entire time.
My bet is he used some rather unsightly methods to achieve that.
恐らく
よほど醜い手を使ったのでしょうね
Regardless, good work on your first job and overtime work.
とにかくだ
残業込みで 初陣お疲れさま
Screw you.
くそったれが
If you follow the rules, then there's no way to outdo them.
ルールに従ってるだけじゃ
ヤツらは出し抜けない
We can't do this by normal means.
普通の方法じゃダメってことさ
You seem to be an important piece for the higher ups.
（土御門）
上にとって お前は
よほど貴重なものらしいからな
Let's work together, Accelerator.
手を結ぼうぜ アクセラレータ
Sounds fun.
（ｱｸｾﾗﾚｰﾀ）
面白え
I warn you though, if you slow me down, I'll ditch you into the gutter.
ただし お前らが足を引っ張んなら
容赦なく切り捨てる
フッ… 威勢のいい小僧だ
I like that attitude, kid.
Come.
ついてこい
そろそろ上の連中に反撃しようぜ
It's about time we counterattack the higher ups.
How fun.
（ｱｸｾﾗﾚｰﾀ）
楽しいねえ
Having a goal is really fun.
目的があるっていうのは
本当に楽しい
（美琴）
なによ
Come on...
I even sent a text message...
せっかく こっちから
メール出したってのに
Why hasn't she replied?
なんで返事来ないのよ
The mountain of documents doesn't seem to shrink no matter how much I do...
（黒子(くろこ)）
やってもやっても―
書類の山が
なくならないですの
hitori de ii to tsubuyaita toaru sekai no chuushin de
In the center of a certain world, I whispered "I'm okay by myself"
We can't do anything about it with everyone else out of commission.
（初春(ういはる)）
しかたないですよ
みんな倒れてたんだから
You should be ready to keep this up for another 3 days.
あと軽～く３日は
覚悟してくださいね
tokei no hari wo orimagete hitomi tojiteta
I closed my eyes as the hands of the clock turned
sugisatta toki wa modosenai kedo
We can't bring back the past
（小萌(こもえ)）
へえ～！
ano hi oshietekureta yo ne
But you told me that day
An emporium of interception weapons?
迎撃兵器ショーの
コンパニオンですか
sore de iin da to
"It's okay this way"
But in reality, it's just a powered suit demonstration.
（黄泉川(よみかわ)）
つっても
パワードスーツの―
デモンストレーション
じゃん
So you're basically wearing a costume.
meguri meguru kisetsu ni kimi ga ita kiseki
In the passing seasons, with the miracle of you being there for me
（芳川(よしかわ)）
それって 要するに
着ぐるみでしょう？
Th-That's a little harsh...
そ… それは
言い過ぎじゃんよ
kowareteta tokei sae ugokidasu kara
Even the broken clock begins to move again
（吹寄(ふきよせ)）
ハァ…
This pudding tastes pretty good for a convenience store brand.
（姫神(ひめがみ)）
このプリン
コンビニのにしては―
ima wa sou muryoku na garakuta dakedo
And though I may not be powerful now
バカにならない味
You'll get fat if you eat sweet things at night.
（舞夏(まいか)）
夜に甘い物食べると
太るんだぞ
fushigi da ne kaerareru sonna ki ga suru
It's strange how I feel that I can go back
"Where is he?" asks MISAKA asks MISAKA.
（ラストオーダー）
あの人は どこって―
ミサカはミサカは
尋ねてみたり
kimi no koe ga ima mo mada koko ni aru kara
Even now, I can still hear your voice right next to me
He'll be back soon.
（カエル医者）
戻ってくるよ
すぐにね
"Okay."
うん　ミサカも早く会いたいって
ミサカはミサカは うなずいてみる
"MISAKA wants to see him soon," nods MISAKA nods MISAKA.
Good night.
おやすみ
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）あっ 当麻！
（上条）あっ！
Touma!
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）
もう！　また１人で出かけて
大ケガするなんて
You went running off and got yourself beaten up yet again!
I never understand the reasoning behind your actions!
相変わらず 当麻の行動は
ワケが分からないんだよ
あ～ いや
今回は まだ運が良かったほう…
Well, uh...
Actually this time, I was probably on the lucky side—
…て
I take it back! Such misfortune!!
（上条）
やっぱり不幸だーっ！